# CHRIS TAEYOUNG KIM

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

christaeyoung.kim@gmail.com

+1-647-268-0246

Toronto, ON Canada

linkedin.com/in/chris-ty-kim/

github.com/chriskimty

## **PROFILE**

Front-end developer passionate about creating clean, responsive, accessible, and creative web designs using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React and API Integrations, with 8+ years in the education sector. Excellent interpersonal and communication skills, leadership, teamwork, problem-solving, adaptability, and ability to work under pressure.

## **EDUCATION**

#### Juno College of Technology

- Web Development Certificate | Nov 2022
- Web Development Course | Aug 2022

#### York University

• Bachelor of Education | 2018-20

#### **University of Toronto**

- MA Music Education | 2016-17
- Honours BMus | 2013-16

## SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS3, SCSS
- JavaScript ES6
- React.js, node.js
- RESTful APIs, Firebase
- Github, Git
- Web Accessibility
- Responsive Design
- Paired programming & team Attention to detail based development
- Project scope management

- Communication
- Critical Thinking
- Leadership
- Teamwork/Collaboration
- Problem Solving
- Organization
- Creativity

### RECENT PROJECTS

## **Queen Quotes** JS | REST APIs | SCSS | HTML Repo



- A quiz app where the user guesses which Drag Race Queen said a famous quote based on randomized data from the API
- Pair-programming project using RESTful APIs, JavaScript, DOM manipulation, error handling and UI design

## **BeachStays** JS | SCSS | HTML



Live Repo

- A multi-page PSD conversion
- Fully responsive and accessible design
- Functional UI elements with JavaScript including a hamburger menu, form submissions and image carousel

## **Tasty** HTML | CSS



- HTML/CSS PSD conversion
- Fully responsive and accessible design
- The conversion project adheres to style guide requirements

### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Toronto District School Board | Oct 2020 - present Secondary Teacher

- Created intellectually rich and socially inclusive in-person and virtual classrooms, and aimed to reach all students (100+ students per semester) through incorporating effective and interactive educational technologies such as Nearpod, Peardeck, Flipgrid, Padlet, Mentimeter, Soundtrap, BandLab, GarageBand, Flat.io etc.
- Coordinated a year-end Music and Arts Concert between two schools which reached a 300+ community audience
- Raised OSSLT scores from 92-98% through targeted extra-help

#### York University | May - Aug 2020

Research Assistant (Department of Computational Arts)

• Assisted in creating a resource guide for digital music technology aimed to help classroom music teachers increase use of emerging music technologies in their classroom - in response to COVID-19 remote teaching. Successfully presented and implemented a resource guide to support the 50+ staff at the Community Music Schools of Toronto.

#### Helen Ziegler & Associates Inc. | May 2017 - Aug 2018 **Recruitment Coordinator**

- Provided support in recruiting and screening potential healthcare candidates for accredited hospitals in the Arabian Peninsula, and tracked the status of candidate requirements, licensing procedures, and contract offers for over 50 candidates at a time
- Received a promotion from Recruitment Assistant to Recruitment Coordinator, as well as 2 pay raises in under 12 months

#### Community Music Schools of Toronto | Jan 2017 - present Faculty

- Taught music through online platforms during COVID-19 restrictions (Zoom and asynchronous teaching via creating YouTube videos and utilizing digital technologies), reaching a total student body of 700+ students in Regent Park, Jane and Finch, and more
- Prior to the pandemic, taught K-12 students in a classroom-setting, urban community school and developed creative resources to meet student interests and learning needs, collaborating with 50+ staff